Drop anchor!
The perfect setting
to inspire our new heist.
Let me tell you about an idea
I've been mulling over.
Yeah? What idea?
Robbing a bank's safety-deposit boxes.
But not just any bank.
The one with the most safety-deposit boxes
in the country, 7,624.
These are private boxes in a bank's vault,
but with a twist.
No one asks what's inside them.
Supposedly they contain jewels, gold…
But you know what the truth is?
People hide their undeclared money there.
You're telling me to rob safety-deposit
boxes without knowing their contents?
What's that? A surprise robbery?
No. I'm talking
about the bank of Marbella.
They've had to add more boxes three times.
You know why?
Because Marbella's a stinking rich town,
where Russian multimillionaires coexist
with Arab sheiks
and every Mafia you can think of.
The Lebanese, Italians, Moroccans…
What do you think people keep there?
Their grandmas' trinkets? No.
Undeclared money and gold bars.
Shall we take a dip?
We can do it over Christmas.
Christmas Eve falls on a Friday this year.
Christmas, on Saturday.
Counting Sunday, we have three days
to bust into that vault
and loot the boxes.
I'm not spending Christmas in some hole,
robbing boxes filled with God knows what.
I told you, undeclared money.
Indecent amounts. I'd stake my life on it.
My friend, can you guarantee those boxes
hold more than 15 million euros in cash?
Forget jewels and gold bars.
What do you propose?
Coming here to a nautical event
for millionaires?
The vintage sailing World Cup.
No, this is just where we cast our nets.
Mingling with multimillionaires
is the best way to reach our goal.
Think about those two words.
"Multi" and "millionaires."
Where do you think the term comes from?
Them having multiple millions.
If you want to mingle with them,
why aren't we in Monaco?
Please, don't be old-fashioned.
Here, we have
adventure-loving multimillionaires,
who explore the world
in classic sailboats.
They're the ones we want. You know why?
Because they think
they're like you and me.
They espouse neo-hippism
and wear T-shirts instead of suits.
Like that Facebook dude.
They pretend to be
just like everyone else.
San Sebastián is the new Monaco.
And how will we choose who to rob?
That's one of the things I like the most
about a heist.
The seduction.
It's not enough
to choose an obscenely rich mark.
You have to gain their trust.
Gain access to their circle of friends
and get close.
Then find out how they manage
their fortune, where they keep it,
and if they have secrets.
And then pick them clean
before they see it coming,
leaving no scraps.
So that's why we're here. To seduce.
Shall we get started?
Good evening. Excuse me.
My friend was just saying
he loves your dress
and it suits you wonderfully.
How kind. My name's Margarita.
- Pleasure.
- And you are…?
Ricardo Pérez Infante. He owns
a shipping company in North Africa.
But do go on talking, please.
I'll pop out for a minute
to look at the boats.
- I own a shipping company too.
- Do you?
In another country.
- What a coincidence.
- Indeed.
My necklace.
Careful. May I?
Please.
Thank you. It'll just be a moment.
Let's see.
I think you're not missing any.
Thank you so much.
I noticed the clasp was loose
when I put it on.
May I?
Careful with the hair. That's it.
See, sometimes the spring rings
don't have the same carats,
and the difference in materials
dilates with time, making them loose.
I can tell you're an expert in jewelry.
No, more of an amateur.
My grandfather was a jeweler. In Paris.
And you are…?
My name's Simón. Nice to meet you.
And I do know who you are.
Genoveva Dante, Duchess of Málaga.
A pleasure.
- Charmed.
- Likewise.
Excuse me, Ms. Genoveva.
Your car awaits you.
I'm sorry.
I'd love to continue this conversation,
but I have other engagements.
Shall I walk you out?
All right.
This is turning out to be
one of the best parties of my life.
Such a shame you couldn't stay any longer,
but it's a delightful soirée.
- Will I see you at dinner?
- I'm leaving for Seville now.
I understand perfectly well.
You live in one of the city's
most beautiful spots.
Are you familiar with my palace?
Let's say every time I walk by,
I am intrigued and stop
just to admire the façade.
I imagine the inside
is an architectural gem.
Would you like to see it?
I'd love to.
And with you as my hostess,
the pleasure will be double.
How about next week?
Could it be in two weeks' time?
Lately, I travel by boat,
and things move at a different speed.
I'll be waiting.
How did it go with that lady?
Did you find her dentures in the G&T?
Very funny.
Who is she?
The millionaire we're going to rob.
Duchess, some chocolates.
- There was no need for that.
- Please, it's my pleasure.
Come with me.
You can't imagine
how happy I am to have you here.
Will you show me the whole palace now?
Later. There will be time
for an art class after.
First, there's something that can't wait.
Oh, really?
- What is it?
- A surprise.
You'll see. It's this way.
I'm so happy you accepted my invitation.
I was really looking forward
to meeting you.
My wife told me you're a great admirer
of Seville in general
and of my house in particular.
I noticed from the outside it has
Neo-Gothic and Neo-Mudéjar sections.
And Neo-Renaissance.
I'll show it to you myself.
There's your art class.
I'll go make sure
they're chilling the chocolates.
In this heat…
Thank you, darling.
Shall we take a seat?
Please.
When I said I was looking forward
to meeting you, it was true.
I've heard good things.
Very good things about you.
I wonder from whom.
You're a brilliant man.
What's more, I'd say you're a genius.
I admire your talent,
your impeccable career,
devoid of ups and downs…
Never left a single clue for the police.
What's this, Your Grace?
A veiled threat?
No, please. Don't take it the wrong way.
I won't blackmail you.
I won't ask you
about the whereabouts of that chalice.
It belonged to a good friend of mine,
but he’s accepted that it’s gone.
I'm an authentic admirer of yours,
and that's why I brought you here.
I have a business proposition.
I want you to steal
a painting by Leonardo da Vinci,
the Lady with an Ermine.
You know the piece?
It's one of four female portraits
Leonardo painted.
It's currently in Kraków,
at the Czartoryski Museum.
Amazing. See how amazing? Precisely.
But it's coming to Seville
for a Renaissance-themed exhibit,
and it will be
at the old Merced Calzada convent.
The current Fine Arts Museum.
Isn't it a sign from destiny that the lady
is coming to my city when she's…
what I most desire?
"What he most desires," said the knave.
He admires and respects me,
like I'm the pope.
- Who admires you?
- The duke.
He ambushed me, brought me here
under false pretenses.
Sent me his wife, who's very beautiful,
as a lure, knowing I'm a gentleman
and couldn't possibly refuse her.
But why? What does he want?
He showed me a photo
of the chalice we stole.
Where did he get it?
Who gave him that information?
How's that relevant now, Damián?
All that matters is this guy
expects me to steal for him.
Who does he think I am? A thieving pawn?
Do I look like an intermediary,
a robber for hire?
Am I an errand boy?
You know full well
my heists are masterpieces,
not contract jobs for a nincompoop.
Well, turning him down is enough.
I didn't say no.
- Did you say yes?
- Not that either.
I said I'd think about it.
Jesus, Seville is so hot.
But…
- Why did you say that to him?
- We're going to teach him a lesson.
I'll exact my revenge
for the way he treated me.
Wait, Andrés, how do you plan
on getting revenge?
Don't they say
it's no crime to steal from a thief?
We'll rob him blind.
That's it. We were looking
for someone to rob.
His entitled Grace is perfect,
because he's more of a crook than we are.
And he can't report us.
- Andrés, you're not thinking straight.
- No, I'm thinking this guy knows us.
He knows you too.
Saying no could be counterproductive.
We'll say yes, then we'll rob him.
He won't be able to do a thing.
Are you with me?
Round up the crew.
Candela, calm down!
What? Want me to calm down?
There. Get out of my house this minute!
- Here, take your shit!
- Candela, have you lost your mind?
I'll go down there,
and you'll really see me lose it.
- Didn't I tell you to leave?
- Candela.
- Can you tell me what I did?
- You disrespected me with your cousin.
Candela, please.
Nothing happened with her.
- Leave.
- I don't know how to tell you.
- What are you staring at?
- Nothing, ma'am.
"Ma'am." That's the last straw.
I was just thinking how fortunate I am
not to be that guy.
You're about to keel over.
You look as hot as a festival horse.
And to think my suit's 100% linen.
But it doesn't make a difference.
Sometimes I wonder how you can live here
at over 100 degrees in the shade.
Our blood runs hot.
We reach boiling point in seconds.
Since there are so many of us,
the city heats up like a bubbling pot.
Don't you ever feel like moving
to Switzerland?
- Or someplace like that?
- "Switzerland," he says. Hilarious.
This is for you.
You look like someone who likes music.
The south has some great things too.
Flamenco, the Guadalquivir,
orange trees, orange blossoms…
And over 300 Sevillian sculptures
of the virgin.
- And The Passion.
After witnessing this quarrel,
and leaving aside the vexation,
there was more passion there
than many get to experience in a lifetime.
We like to live life above the hilt,
you know?
- No.
- What?
The phrase is "to the hilt."
- No.
- It is.
"Above the hilt" sounds a bit too gory.
Look, this is a gift too.
When you listen to it, you'll think of me.
- Thank you.
- One more thing.
If you don't want to be hot
in this 100-degree weather,
don't wear a jacket, handsome.
Goodbye.
- Need a hand?
- No, I'm fine.
Are you sure?
I told the crew.
They'll be here in 48 hours.
- Very well.
- What's that?
That woman just stole my wallet
like she was David Copperfield.
She gave me the records, talked to me,
and pushed me at the same time
to divert my attention twice,
so she could reach into both my pockets.
She took it as if by levitation.
Not even brushing against me.
A thing of beauty.
What did you have in it?
Nothing, just 600 or 700 euros.
Hey. Theft by sleight-of-hand is an art.
- Of course. Yes.
- I don't mind paying for it at all.
It is.
Either that or you just want
to come back for your wallet.
After the Paris heist,
Bruce was as stimulated by Keila
as he was confused by her.
She was the 34th woman he had ever kissed,
but this time,
he felt like doing things with her
he had never done with anyone else.
Like waiting for her at the hair salon.
Or sitting in a theater with no idea
what movie they were catching.
And one day, while looking
at a Christmas shop window…
Keila.
…he said something
for the first time ever.
Want to move in together?
Yes!
Yes.
After two weeks together,
and coming to the realization
he didn't feel like fleeing,
Bruce knew he was deeply in love
and that the old Bruce was dead.
So he decided
to throw a farewell party for him.
He invited his friends and family,
and the people from his hometown.
Over 1,500 people attended.
At that party, Bruce said goodbye
to excess, alcohol, reggaeton,
and one-night stands.
Dressed up as a wedding-cake groom,
with Keila by his side,
also in a bride costume,
he came out onto the balcony
to tell the world he had found her.
But, as Bruce
left that life behind triumphantly,
Keila, almost by accident,
entered it.
Sometimes, the silliest moment
can lead you straight to hell.
Roi also experienced life as a couple.
But, unlike Bruce and Keila,
for him, it was epic from the beginning.
They started living in a cabin
far away from the rest of the world,
like two Robinson Crusoes.
Some nights, they'd take their bed outside
to watch the Perseids meteor shower.
Sometimes, they'd fall asleep there.
What happiness!
Cameron said then
that when you're fulfilled,
you can sleep anywhere.
When they grew tired of the countryside,
they got on their bike and went into town.
They lived wherever they wanted
and however they wanted.
But something
must've gone wrong along the way
because they arrived separately
and none of us saw them
speak to each other.
Everybody had their love story,
myself included.
But mine was a chaste romance…
with Damián.
Once the adrenaline
from the Paris heist subsided,
Confronted with the idea
of returning to an empty house,
Damián became obsessed
with never letting that moment arrive.
He would drag out his lessons
and his office hours.
He even joined the professors'
padel league.
But still, there always came a time
when the university closed for the day.
I bought a suitcase
and a plane ticket to Singapore
to meet with Camille,
but someone kept lurking
around my place every day.
He'd come, go,
double-park and, when he'd see me go by,
he'd pretend to bump into me by chance.
Hey, Andrés. What a coincidence.
I'm going to the supermarket.
The university's is closed.
Want to grab a beer?
Or go to the movies or…?
We could get Korean food.
I realized my friend desperately needed
to travel with a buddy
and share his feelings.
And share, he did.
He shared in Vancouver,
in Arizona,
in Tulum.
He shared in Medellín
and in Rio de Janeiro…
At no point during that trip
did he stop talking
until we reached Argentina.
And there, in Patagonia,
when we saw that glacier break away
and plunge into the depths,
just as his life had, he understood
that it was time for him to rise up.
Should we go home?
Okay. We have everything.
Let's get started.
I'm sure you're all wondering
why we're in Seville.
We've been asked to steal this portrait.
The Lady with an Ermine.
Painted by Leonardo da Vinci in 1489,
its value is estimated
at over 300 million euros.
It's at the Czartoryski Museum in Krákow.
In ten days, it will come to Seville
for a Renaissance exhibit.
But we're not stealing her.
Excuse me.
In fact, the appropriate question here
and now is not what we'll be stealing,
but from whom.
Álvaro Hermoso de Medina,
the individual who requested our services
for that unfortunate heist.
Proceed.
He hails from an old Spanish noble family
and lives in one of Seville's
most important palaces.
Over 8,000 square meters of cloisters,
gardens, and stables…
There's even a church.
He owns a famous sherry winery
and breeds fighting bulls.
He's a master bullfighter on horseback.
And why does an aristocrat
with a long lineage, a palace,
and wineries want a stolen painting?
That's exactly what I asked him.
Lady with an Ermine is no doubt
stimulating for its beauty,
but also for its incalculable
monetary value.
Is it for you, or do you want
to trade it on the black market?
Well, that doesn't concern you.
But let's say I want it for myself.
As the crowning jewel of my collection.
You don't say.
I'd love to see your collection.
As you'll understand,
for security reasons,
or rather, for logical reasons,
I won't show a professional
such as yourself where I keep it.
That collection is what we're after.
- What kind is it?
- What kind is what?
The collection.
We don't know yet.
Come on. You can't be serious.
You pass on a bank's safety-deposit boxes
because you don't know what's in them,
but we will steal a collection
of God knows what.
That eccentric
could be a rabid stamp collector,
or he could have cookie tins full of coins
or a collection of ancient pottery.
Pottery!
No one who orders a da Vinci
would display it with lesser pieces.
If that is the crowning jewel,
imagine the regalia.
I have a feeling that collection
is an extraordinary treasure.
The treasure box you came to Seville for
is the duchess's.
I saw you in San Sebastián.
The flirting and giggles on the stairs.
You brought me sailing
from the Cantabrian coast
and on the Atlantic all the way to Seville
for the promise of a date.
But it left a bad taste in your mouth
that it was all a ruse
to introduce you to her husband.
A heist is surgery and cold heads.
Not the hotheaded whim
of a spiteful man after a duke.
You'll drag us all
into your uncertain and risky plan
out of a bruised ego and hubris.
And you?
Want to tell them
where you want to take me?
He wants to stick me in a hole
to rob safety-deposit boxes
with a plumber's blowtorch
on Christmas Eve and Christmas Day
just because he’s got no one
to have Christmas dinner
or sing carols with.
Let's do this.
Whoever wants to rob
Damián's little surprise boxes
can get off this boat now,
take their things, and leave.
Those who want to discover what's
hiding in His Grace the Duke's collection
stay.
Fine.
I'll stay too.
Let's hit that collection,
and then I'll go with whoever volunteers
to rob those boxes in Marbella.
Then we'll see
which heist made more sense.
This city is beautiful.
Especially at night,
when no one's around
and the suffocating heat subsides.
And yet, the orange blossom scent
lingers in the air.
Breathe in the aroma, Roi.
Do you smell it?
- I do.
- Delightful.
Sir, where are we going?
To see if you've lost your touch
over the last few months.
Open that door for me.
Come on.
Fantastic.
Now this one.
Sir, this has to do
with the collection, right?
What collection?
The duke's.
Let's say only tangentially.
Go on.
How wonderful.
I'll handle this.
Go back to the boat with the others.
They might still be busy
with the research.
You shot me.
They're just pellets.
It's my cousin's fair shotgun.
- What are you doing in my house?
- Retrieving the wallet you stole.
Then ring the doorbell,
like everyone else.
Next time, I'll aim for your eye.
I think I have something.
These are the duke's income tax returns.
He has three big companies.
The cattle business, El Hermoso wineries,
and a boat-rental company.
Luxury vacation boats.
If you're not loaded, don't even bother.
- What do you think?
- I don't know, Cameron.
A rental business
doesn't help me figure out
where he might be hiding
this mysterious collection of his.
I feel like a substitute teacher.
The literature teacher
who stands in for the physics guy.
This isn't even my heist.
I have something, if you wanna see it.
I hacked emails, correspondence,
invoices, bank accounts,
purchases, commissions…
So you've uncovered this dog's
every little secret.
In 1999, he had unusual remodeling done
on his property,
25 miles outside of Seville.
He built a sort of underground train
from his house to one of the wineries.
Isn't that a bit odd?
Here's another odd thing.
In 2000, one year later,
he moved everything from that winery
to his wineries in Jerez de la Frontera
and shut it down.
How strange, spending money on
a private train to a closed business.
In his 2000 tax return,
he deducted a million-euro invoice.
From Nitax Private Security,
a security firm from Geneva.
The property's address is
in the description.
That's Sotheby's
and the Louvre's security firm.
It's on their website.
Why would anyone care so much
about protecting their empty winery,
just a short ride from their home
on their own little train?
If that duke has a valuable collection,
it's in there.
Keep at it.
Where's Berlin? I want to go to my cabin.
He can handle the research.
Yeah. The thing is,
we went for a walk around Seville.
- Just walking the streets.
- Right.
And he stayed there.
It wouldn't happen to be around
Patio de Banderas Square?
- That's right.
- Number 22?
- Yes.
- Second floor?
- Fuck my life.
First his treasure and the collection,
and now the record-throwing woman.
I'm going to bed.
It stings.
Stings?
Maybe you could take him
off the bed for a bit?
Why?
It's not the most hygienic,
given the circumstances.
My Pomelo is very clean.
Besides, he's still shaken,
the poor thing.
- Let's get the other one.
- Be careful.
Here it is.
Do you always
greet your guests by shooting them?
You were not a guest.
Besides, I thought you were someone else.
- Who?
- My boyfriend.
Well, my ex-boyfriend.
He broke in to steal
a shoebox where I had 6,000 euros,
and he knew I have
a cookie tin with more money,
but he didn't find it.
I thought he'd come looking for it.
With that mystery cleared up,
if you give me back my wallet,
I might ask you out to dinner.
Or rather, breakfast.
- That won't be possible.
- Why?
Because the wallet was in the shoebox.
But you know what?
Since he stole your wallet and my money,
you're coming with me to get it back.
- How about it?
- Well, if we must go…
- You can wear my boyfriend's T-shirt.
- A T-shirt? No.
Impossible.
- Do you have children?
- Me? No.
Want anything from the store? Chocolate?
No, thanks. I'm fine.
I'll wait until breakfast.
Okay.
All right.
There, all set.
Ole, María.
I don't embroider handkerchiefs
You don't tear up contracts
I don't kill out of jealousy
You don't die for me
And before you love me
Like one loves a cat
I take up with anyone
Who reminds me of you
I leave my doors wide open…
- We're going that way.
- Whatever you say, ma'am.
The peace you've chosen
Is worse than my war
What could have been
And what will never be
I never knew
How to go with the wind
Which bites the corners
Of this ungodly city
Poor sorcerer's apprentice
Spitting into the starry night sky…
Shall we?
Need help?
- Bon appétit.
- Thanks, Candela.
I'll show you. You're in for it now.
Where's my money?
What, no one home?
You're in bed, huh?
Well, I'll wake you up.
Are you asleep?
Wake up, baby.
Are you tired?
Let's see if this wakes you up.
We can't sleep!
Hey, Candela!
Candela, what did you do? Open the door.
Open up! You're gonna kill me!
Open the door! What are you doing?
The gas tank's gonna blow!
- Give me back my box first.
- What? I didn't do anything!
Really? Just like you didn't do anything
with your cousin.
- Candela.
- What?
I swear to God
nothing happened with my cousin.
- Right.
- Open up!
Get away from the door.
We can't sleep!
Hey! Stay back. This doesn't involve you.
Get back! This is between the two of us.
Come on. Stick your head out and swear it
so I can see your eyes.
I swear. Now open the damn door!
I can see you're lying.
The same way I saw you ogling your cousin.
And you keep denying it.
"She's like a sister to me.
We grew up together."
Yet, she climbs onto your bike,
chest pressed against you.
And what about that time in the pool?
Riding on your shoulders,
her thighs wrapped around you.
Look at me. All right?
- This place is gonna blow. Open up!
- Blow? Don't be silly.
And when you went
to her wedding dress fitting?
How is that normal?
People take their mothers,
sisters, or friends.
But male cousins? No way.
Where are you going with that hose?
Help me!
Wanna feel my hammer?
Candela, you're going too far.
- Oh, am I?
- You'll regret this.
Me? I never regret anything.
- Candela…
- Come on.
- Go away.
- Please.
Listen up, everybody!
There's nothing going on here, okay?
Everyone, calm down. We can fix this.
Drop the hose. I can see you.
- So?
- Please.
Did it turn you on
to see her dressed in white?
Stick your head out. I can't see you!
- Candela, please.
- What?
Did you fuck her that day? Tell me.
Did you fuck her, yes or no?
Okay. Yeah.
Only that one day, Candela.
And I was still crazy about you.
I mean it.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
I'm even more sorry.
Candela!
Show's over!
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
I'm happy to have slammed the door
on my old life.
I looked like a dangerous lunatic, huh?
When you shot me in the chest
or when you set a trailer on fire?
No, what happened earlier
was funny, right?
Even Pomelo took a liking to you.
I meant just now,
with the gasoline and all that.
No, you struck me as very brave.
Oh, really?
One must fall out of love
the same way one fell in.
People languish in their farewells.
Many spend months, even years,
summoning up the courage to end things,
and sometimes,
they don't even get to do it.
That's sad and infuriating.
Few things are as sad as watching
your love die little by little.
Having to fake headaches
to keep your distance.
Or worse,
you begin pretending every morning,
until one day, after three years,
you maybe dare to say it, and then
and then you start to putting their things
in perfectly-packed boxes.
That's not me. As you've seen,
I'm more the toss-it-out-the-window type.
If you enter someone's life
through open doors,
the only dignified way to leave it is
by slamming the door.
Just what we needed.
You could use that T-shirt now.
Wait, let me help you. There.
- Good evening, officer.
- Good evening. Where are you coming from?
We were visiting a friend in San Roque.
Your car smells like gas.
We just filled the tank.
Turn off your engine.
License and registration, please.
Of course. Right away.
Simón, hand me the papers
in the glove compartment, honey.
I also need your driver's license, ma'am.
Finding it in this mess won't be easy.
I have so much stuff in here.
I mean, I just can't find it.
There's a lot of stuff.
Just give me a minute.
Don't leave the vehicle.
Why is everything going wrong tonight?
Blue car. Plates 212D B.
Here, your wallet.
What? I forgot I had it in my bag.
Have it in case
they ask for your papers too.
Which they will.
Why do you think
they'll ask for my papers?
I don't have a license,
and this isn't my car.
That is to say, it's stolen.
Right.
I thought as much
when I saw you hot-wiring the ignition.
- They sandwiched us.
- What?
Oh my God. That's it, then.
If they catch me with a stolen car again,
I'll get four years.
But if I run, it'll be six.
So tell me, should I risk it?
Hold on.
What are you doing?
Switch places with me.
Risk it?
The plates match a stolen vehicle.
I repeat, it's a stolen vehicle.
Rock and roll.
Subtitle translation by:
Soledad Etchemendy